George H. Smyser Papers
George H. Smyser Papers
1863-1955
Smyser, George H.
1.0 linear feet
Papers of the Abraham Lincoln collector and scholar. Collection includes correspondence, 1905-1955, of Smyser and his wife; and numerous speeches, 1863-1943, about Abraham Lincoln.
148674
Biographical History
George Smyser of Utica, New York was an Abraham Lincoln researcher, collector and scholar.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The George Smyser Papers consist of Correspondence, 1905-1955, of Smyser and his wife, and a collection of Speeches, 1863-1943, mostly about Abraham Lincoln.
Arrangement of the Collection
Both series are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Biography; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; Smyser, George H.; Correspondence.; Speeches (documents); Authors.; Biographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - Angle-Wilson (Box 1)
  - Incoming
    - Incoming, 1905-1938; 8 folders (Box 1)
    - Incoming, 1939-1943; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Incoming, 1945-1955; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Incoming, undated (Box 1)
  - Mrs. Smyser's letters, 1937-1954 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Speeches
  - Speeches, 1863-1925 (Box 2)
    Address delivered at the dedication of the Cemetery at Gettysbury - Nov. 19, 1863
    The Garrett Letter - Oct. 24, 1907
    What would Lincoln do today Feb. 12, 1908
    Abraham Lincoln - Feb. 14, 1909
    Gentlemen of the Graduates Club - Feb. 12, 1910
    Address of the Secretary of the Navy at the Lincoln Day, Dinner of the Republican Club of the City of New York Feb. 13, 1911
    Abraham Lincoln - Feb. 14, 1914
    Address of Hon. Newton D. Baker, Secretary of War - Sept. 4, 1916
    Complimentary Banquet to Mr. T. P. - Oct. 30, 1923
    "Abraham Lincoln as a Potential Lion" - May 16, 1924
    For The Press - Feb. 11, 1925
    Address of James J. Davis Feb. 12, 1925
    Remarks at Lincoln Club Banquet - Reh. 12, 1925
    Lincoln and Religion - Feb. 15, 1925
    Address by Senator James W. Wadsworth, Jr. - Sept. 9, 1925
  - Speeches, 1926-1939 (Box 2)
    Address on Abraham Lincoln - Feb. 12, 1926
    Lincoln's Task - and Ours - March 18, 1926
    Paul Brown - June 11, 1930
    Introduction of President Herbert Hoover At Dedication Ceremonies of Remodeled Tome of Lincoln - June 17, 1931
    Mid - Dai Lincoln Club - Feb. 11, 1932
    Republican National Committee - Feb. 12, 1932 Con't LIST OF SPEECHES
    Rupublican National Committee - Feb. 12, 1932
    "Lincoln and Today" - Feb. 12, 1932
    An address by the President - Feb. 12, 1932
    The America I Want - May 19, 1939
  - Speeches, 1940-1943 (Box 2)
    Postmaster Abraham Lincoln - Feb. 12, 1940
    Abraham Lincoln - Feb. 10, 1940
    A Creed For Republicans - Feb. 11, 1940
    "America Must Be On Guard - Feb. 12, 1940
    Address of Lieutenant Governor Charles Poletti - Feb. 12, 1940
    Senator Taft's Lincoln Day Address Feb. 13, 1940
    From Bert Sheldon - Feb. 7, 1949
    The Cavalcade of America - May 7, 1940
    The Cavalcade of America and The Perfect Tribute - Feb. 8, 1943
  - Speeches, undated (Box 2)
    Nathan Townsend
    Lincoln's Birthday
    Dr. J. M. Puig Casauranc
    The Autobiography of Abraham Lincoln (2 copies)